《永远的蝙蝠侠》
我可以劝你带上三明治吗 先生？
Can I persuade you to take a sandwich?
我自己去买
I'll get drive-through.
你在希望那个长翅膀的复仇者救你出去
You're counting on the winged avenger to deliver you from evil.
是吗 我的朋友？
aren't you, my friend?
你要杀死我吗？
Are you going to kill me?
也许 也许不 因为这件世上我们总有两种意见
Maybe, maybe not. We're of two minds on the subject.
要赌博吗？
You a gambling man?
咱们扔硬币决定吧？
What say we flip for it?
有的人天生彪悍骁勇 而他的弟弟可能是胆小如鼠
One man is born a hero, his brother a coward.
朱门酒肉臭
Babies starve, politicians grow fat.
路有冻死骨
holy men are martyred, and junkies grow legion.
告诉我 为什么？
Why?
为什么？为什么？为什么？为什么？为什么？
Why, why, why, why, why?
运气！
Luck!
盲目的 愚蠢的 简单的
Blind, stupid, simple, doo-dah.
毫无规律的运气！
clueless luck!
随手一扔
The random toss.
真正的公正
is the only true justice.
让我们来看看什么样的运气在
Let's see what justice has in store.
等待着你
for you.
就象上帝的触摸
It's like the touch of God.
等等 等等 等等 让我们来看看是什么
Wait, wait, wait.
哦 幸运的微笑 对你来说 又一个美酒玫瑰日
Fortune smiles. Another day of wine and roses.
对你来说 就是啤酒和披萨饼
In your case, beer and pizza.
行动吧 伙计们！
Out of here, guys!
- 你说过会让我活下去的！- 太对了！
- But you said you'd let me live! - Too true!
你会活下去！没有比诱惑蝙蝠更有趣的事了
And so you shall! Nothing's better than live bait to trap a bat.
真精彩的出场
Hot entrance.
双面人？
Two-Face?
已经死了两个警卫了
2 guards are dead.
他抓着第三个警卫当人质
He's holding a third hostage. Didn't see this one coming.
我们应该能想到
We should have.
纽约第二个银行
The 2nd Bank of Gotham.
两周年纪念那天我抓到过他
2nd anniversary of the day I captured him.
他怎么能抵抗得住你呢？
How could he resist?
我是切斯 马瑞典
I'm Chase Meridian.
我邀请她来这里帮助这个案子 她的专长是
I asked her to come to here to consult on the case. She specializes in.
变态心理学 多重人性研究学 我读过你的专著
Psychology, multiple personalities. I read your work.
非常不错
Insightful.
朴实 很有见解
Naive, but insightful.
我受宠惹惊 不是每个女士的书都能放到你的床头柜上
I'm flattered. Not every girl makes a superhero's night table.
我们不能他讲道理
Can we reason with him?
- 他扣押了一个无辜的人质 - 不会有什么好事的
- He's got innocent people up there. - It won't do any good.
- 他会不加思索地杀了他 - 我同意
- He'll slaughter them without a thought. - Agreed.
创伤足可以使一个人判若两人 成为双重人物
A trauma powerful enough to create an alternate personality leaves one.
尤其是在一个是非混淆的世界里
In a world where normal rules of right and wrong no longer apply.
非常正确
Exactly.
就象你
Like you.
我看我可以写一本书关于把 自己打扮成会飞的啮齿动物的人
I could write a hell of a paper on a grown man dressing like a flying rodent.
蝙蝠不是啮齿动物马瑞典博士
Bats aren't rodents, Dr. Meridian.
真的吗？这我不知道呢
Really? I didn't know that.
你真的很有趣
You are interesting.
叫我切斯吧
And call me Chase.
随便问一句 你有名字吗 还是就是蝙蝠？
By the way, do you have a first name, or do I call you Bats?
砰的一声 晚会开始！
Start the party with a bang!
非常准时 就算是他自己的葬礼 我的孩子们！
Very punctual, even for his own funeral. Boys!
杀死蝙蝠！
Kill the Bat!
杀死他！
Blast him!
芝麻开门
Open sesame.
你中计了！
It's a trap!
纽约市的好市民们 请注意了！
Attention citizens of fair Gotham!
打开保险箱 就能得到我们梦寐以求的东西
When we open that safe, we'll have everything we ever wanted.
钞票象雨一样落在混乱的人群中
enough cash to rain down upon fair Gotham a glorious flood of chaos.
当然
And, of course.
而你 我的朋友 只有死！
you, my boy, dead!
那是沸腾的盐酸！
It's boiling acid!
为了你的死 我们特意准备了盐酸 它使我们变成今天这样子！
For your dying pleasure, we are serving the acid that made us the men we are!
不！
No!
- 抓紧了 - 好的！
- Hold on. - Yes!
把它拉走！
Haul away!
对！把它拉得远远的！
Yes! Haul away!
- 把手给我 - 别让我掉下去！
- Give me your hand. - Don't let go!
借你这个用一下
I must borrow this.
那是我的助听器！
That's my hearing aid!
多谢
Thanks.
我的鞋都化了！
Wow! My shoes are melting!
救命啊！
No more!
抓紧
Hang on.
抓紧？
Hang on?
快 伙计们 扶他下来
Get him down.
他扶下来
轻一点 轻一点
Take it easy with him.
你会没事的 年青人 镇定一点
You'll be all right. Just stay calm.
这下他跑不了啦！
This'll fix him!
抓紧点 蝙蝠！
Hang on!
让我看看
Let's see.
哦 是的！
Yes!
是的 是的 是的 是的 是的！我太高兴了！
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes! Oh, happy day!
永别了
Farewell forever to that.
你这尖耳朵的夜老鼠！
pointy-eared night rat!
头！
Face!
你需要治疗 投降吧
You need help. Give it up.
好好地去死吧！
Have the good taste to die!
再见！
See you!
昨晚 尽管蝙蝠侠尽了所有努力
Despite a valiant effort last night by Batman.
但是 双面人哈利还是逃脱了
Harvey Two-Face is still at large and extremely dangerous.
今天的另一则新闻是
And another news today.
在韦恩集团的电子分部取得了极大的成功之后
billionaire Bruce Wayne extended his profit-sharing program.
亿万富翁布鲁斯 韦恩 扩大了他的员工分享利润计划
to the employees of the successful electronics branch of Wayne Enterprises.
韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne.
您的视察对我们分部是一个极大的鼓舞
Your inspections are a departmental highlight.
天啦 是他
Oh, my God, it's him.
我是个成功者 我是个成功者
I am a winner. I am a winner.
我是个成功者
I am a winner.
生物校正仪 气油替代品
Bioremediation. Alternative fuel.
韦恩先生 时间不早了
Mr. Wayne, look at that time.
我们应该尽快回到研究所去
Perhaps we should get to R & D as soon as possible.
贵姓？
Mister?
布鲁斯 韦恩
Oh, Bruce Wayne.
不 那是我的名字 你的呢？
No, that's my name. And you are?
利格玛
Nygma.
爱德华
Edward.
爱德华利格玛 是您亲自己雇用的
Edward Nygma. You hired me personally.
我也是这样对大家说的
Just like I tell everyone.
实际上 我们从未见过面
We've never actually met,
不过 我的聘用书上有您的签名 我还保留着呢
but your name was on the hiring slip. I have it.
我需要把手拿回来
I need that hand.
哦 是的 当然
Oh, yes, of course.
对不起
I'm sorry.
因为您是
It's just that.
您是我的偶像
you're my idol.
快回去工作
Get to work.
有人痴心妄想要把咱们俩分开
And some people have been trying to keep us apart.
快回去工作
Back to work.
没关系
It's okay.
你的脑子里想些什么？
What's on your mind?
准确地说
Precisely.
是什么在我们的脑子里？
What's on all our minds?
脑电波
Brain waves.
在韦恩企业的未来
The future of Wayne Enterprises.
就是脑电波
is brain waves.
我要向您道歉 韦恩先生
I must apologize, Mr. Wayne.
- 今天早上我已经终止了他的研究项目 - 没关系
- I terminated his project today. - It's okay.
我做出来了！
I have it!
我的发明
My invention.
可以把任何电子信号直接发射到人的大脑中去
beams any TV signal directly into the human brain.
刺激人的神经系统 可以达到操纵人脑电波的目的
By stimulating neurons, manipulating brain waves.
这个装置可以使观众身临其境
this device makes the audience feel like they're inside the show.
为什么要让一个毫无价值的世界 使我们变得粗暴残忍呢？
Why be brutalized by an uncaring world?
你是说「操纵人的脑电波」？
Did you say "manipulating brain waves"?
这个嘛 是的
Yes.
但是
But.
象您这种人永远不需要的
someone like you would never need it.
象您这样
Someone so.
有智慧 有魅力
intelligent, witty and.
谈吐诙谐的人
charming.
我还需要一点点的资金来进行必要的人体试验
I need a bit of additional funding for human trials.
让我 让我做给你看 好吗！
Let me show you, please!
听我说
Now, listen.
把这项目的所有资料和图表给我 好吗？
I want a full set of schematics on this, okay?
咱们俩将是完全的合伙关系 布鲁斯
We'll be full partners in this, Bruce.
你看！我们有多么地相象！
Look at us! Two of a kind!
请打电话给我的助手玛格利塔 她会安排的
You call my assistant, Margaret. She'll set something up.
这对我来说
That's not.
还不够
going to be good for me.
我现在就要答案
I need an answer now.
这是我应得的
I think I deserve it.
抱歉 爱德华 答复是不！
I'm sorry, then the answer is no.
胡乱创改并操纵人的脑电波
Tampering with people's brain waves.
这会引起太多的问题
mind manipulation.
所以我不能答应
it just raises too many questions.
对不起
Sorry.
好 谢谢大家 请继续努力
Thanks, keep up the good work. Looks great.
好了
All right, everyone!
大家回去工作吧！
Back to work!
我回头再跟你算帐！
We'll discuss this later!
你应该明白的
You were supposed to understand.
我会让你明白的
I'll make you understand.
锁门
Lock.
椅子
Chair.
- 阿福 - 我看见信号了 先生
- Alfred. - I saw the signal.
准备好了
All is ready.
局长？
Commissioner?
他在家里
He's home.
信号是我发的
I sent the signal.
出了什么事？
What's wrong?
昨天晚上在银行 我注意到
Last night I noticed something about Two-Face:
双面人的硬币
His coin.
那是他阿基里斯的脚踵
It's his Achilles' heel.
那是他唯一的致命的弱点
It can be exploited.
我知道
I know.
你就是为了这个？
You called me for this?
蝙蝠信号不是寻呼机
The Batsignal is not a beeper.
我希望能说 对你的兴趣仅限于工作
I wish I could say that my interest in you was.
但我不能这么说
purely professional.
你想引诱我吗 博士？
You trying to get under my cape?
一个姑娘不能整天只和精神病人打交道
A girl can't live by psychoses alone.
姑娘们都只喜欢我的车
It's the car, right? Chicks love it.
如果是人呢？
What is it about the wrong kind of man?
在高中的时候 那些带耳环的小伙子吸引我
In grade school: Guys with earrings.
大学时 是摩托车和皮夹
College: Motorcycles, leather jackets.
现在
Now.
黑色橡胶
black rubber.
去找消防队员吧 他们穿得更少
Try a fireman. Less to take off.
这个工作我不介意 遗憾的是 看不见面具下面
I don't mind the work. Pity I can't see behind the mask.
我们都带着面具
We all wear masks.
我是一本打开的书 你想读吗？
My life's an open book. You read?
我不是家庭野餐的好伴侣
I don't blend in at a family picnic.
我们可以试试嘛 我带酒
We could give it a try. I'll bring the wine.
你带你自己就行了
you bring your scarred psyche.
你很直接了当？
Direct, aren't you?
你喜欢强壮的女人吗
You like strong women.
我的工作做完了
I've done my homework.
要不要我穿上紧身衣拿着皮鞭子？
Or do I need skintight vinyl and a whip?
我在女人方面运气一向不好
I haven't had much luck with women.
也许只是你没有遇到合适的
Maybe you just haven't met the right woman.
我看见信号
I saw the signal.
- 出了什么事？- 没事
- What's going on? - Nothing.
是有人误发了信号
False alarm.
你肯定吗？
Are you sure?
女人
Women.
好了 我做好了！
Now I've got it!
太多的问题 是有很多问题
Too many questions. There's too many questions.
很多
Too many.
可是我要让你知道 这能行！
I'll show you it works!
这到底是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on here?!
我跟你说过了 这个项目被终止了！我去叫保卫来！
I told you this project is terminated! I'm calling security!
咖啡因会要了你的命的！
Caffeine will kill you!
该起床了 天竺鼠
Rise and shine, little guinea pig.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
快放开我！
Untie me!
一点都不会疼
This won't hurt.
至少 我认为不会
Least, I don't think it will.
你到底要做什么？
What are you doing?
如果你敢碰那个按纽的话
You touch that switch and.
这个吗？
This?
图像失真
Losing resolution.
加大强度！
More power!
爱德华 利格玛上台了！
Edward Nygma!
你将是电视剧
You're the next contestant on.
吸脑者下一个竞选者
Brain Drain!
我要把你脑袋里的东西都掏出来！
I'll take what's inside thick skull number one!
我们给准备些什么？
What have we got for him?
斯帝格利 我有个突破性的进展！
Oh, Stickley, I'm having a breakthrough!
也许会崩溃！
And a breakdown!
但不管是什么 我是个天才
Nevertheless, I'm smarter. I'm a genius.
不 是几个天才
No, several geniuses.
一群嗡嗡作响的蜜蜂
A gaggle, a swarm.
一大群的弗洛伊德！
a flock of freaking Freuds!
猜个谜语 富莱德
Riddle me this, Fred.
什么东西对一个人最重要
What is everything to someone.
但对其他人却一文不值？
and nothing to everyone else?
是你的思想 宝贝！
Your mind, baby!
现在正在操纵你的思想！
Now mine pumps with the power of yours!
我正在吸收你的IQ
I'm sucking up your IQ.
抽空你的脑皮层
Vacuuming your cortex.
换取你的大脑
Feeding off your brain.
真是惊心动魄！
What a rush!
刚才出了什么事？
What just happened?
一个令人非常惊讶的副作用
A very surprising side effect.
当你呈现在我的三维电视里时
While you were mesmerized by my 3-D TV.
我利用你的中心动力使自己变得聪明
I used your neural energy to grow smarter.
布鲁斯 韦恩说得没错！
Bruce Wayne was right!
你是个坏蛋 不道德的精神病患者！
You demented, bizarre, unethical toad!
这是人脑操纵仪！
It is brain manipulation!
我要向美国通信委员会报告！
I'm reporting you to the FCC!
立即报告人体试验委员会！还有航空材料实验室！
The human experimentation board! The AMI!
还要报警！
And the police!
你会被指控
You are going up on charges.
你将被送上法庭 被审判
to court, to jail.
你会在精神病院度过你的余生！
and then to a mental institution forever!
不过 首先 利格玛 你被解雇了！
But, first and foremost, Nygma, you are fired!
你听到了没有？你被解雇了！
Do you hear me? Fired!
可我不这么想
I don't think so.
救命！
Help!
支持住！
Hang on!
宝贝！
Babe!
你被解雇了！
You are fired!
或者说
Or should I say.
完蛋了？
terminated?
哈哈 跳起来啊老家伙！
Surf's up, Big Kahuna!
姿势不错 可入水不够好
Nice form, but rough on the landing.
绝对不会拿到铜牌的
He may have to settle for the Bronze.
问题？韦恩先生？
Questions, Mr. Wayne?
我的工作会产生太多的问题？
My work raises too many questions.
为什么没有人
Why hasn't anybody.
能让你认清自己呢？
put you in your place?
哈利 登特 前纽约检查官
Harvey Dent, once Gotham's District Attorney.
被地下组织头子莫罗尼严重毁容
was horribly scarred by underworld kingpin, Boss Moroni.
虽然蝙蝠侠极力挽救
Although Batman tried to save him.
但登特仍然变成一个凶残的犯罪份子
Dent's left-brain damage turned him into a violent criminal.
他指责蝙蝠侠 后者发誓要亲手将他抓住
who blamed Batman and who has vowed to destroy him.
双面人哈利 是极端危险的人物 重复一遍 是极端危险的人物
Harvey Two-Face is extremely dangerous, repeat, extremely dangerous.
是戈登局长打来的
That was the Commissioner.
韦恩集团出事故了
There's been an accident at Wayne Enterprises.
这样子死太可怕了
Horrible way to die.
我们这里有电子摄相监视器
The surveillance cameras are down here.
我们会尽快到河里打捞 不过怀疑能否找到尸体
We'll dredge the river, but with that current, I doubt we'll find the body.
为什么？
Why?
这是为什么？
Oh, why?
我真不敢相信
I just can't believe it.
这两年来我们天天在一起工作
Two years working in the same office.
他就象我的父亲
He was like my father.
我的兄弟
my brother.
或表兄
or a cousin that visits a lot.
拿着 爱德华
Get a grip, Edward.
我要桌上发现这个
I found this in my cubicle.
你会发现笔迹和他一模一样 还有句法和拼法也一样
You'll find the handwriting matches his, as does the sentence structure.
我无法在这儿继续工作
I couldn't possibly continue on here.
我的记忆
The memories.
这是昨天晚上保卫科的录象
This is last night's security log.
那是斯帝格利
There's Stickley.
相当明确
Pretty cut and dry.
是的 肯定是自杀
Yes, definitely suicide.
非常感谢 布鲁斯 咱们保持联系
Thanks very much for your help, Bruce. We'll be in touch.
斯帝格利的自杀根本说不通 给他的家人全额补偿
Stickley's suicide doesn't make sense. I want full benefits for his family.
我们的保险条例不包括自杀
Suicide's not covered by our policy.
我知道 全额补偿
I know. Full benefits.
记者歌帝打过32次电话 你找谁谈慈善演出的事儿？
Gossip Gerty called 32 times. Who are you taking to the Charity Circus?
还没定下来 这是什么？
I'll let you know. What's this?
不知道
I don't know.
我没见任何人送来
I didn't see anyone.
「你看我脸上的数
"If you look at the numbers on my face.
永远找不到13「
you won't find 13 anyplace."
真荒唐
That's hideous.
那是什么意思？
What does it mean?
是个谜语
It's a riddle.
「我脸上的数 13 」
"Numbers on my face 13."
1到12
1 through 12.
是钟表
The answer is a clock.
谁给你出谜语？
Who would send you a riddle?
哦 玛格利塔
That, Maggie.
这就是个谜语
is the riddle.
猜猜我今天做了什么？
Guess what I did today?
韦恩庄园
Wayne Manor.
回头见
See you soon.
我要见马瑞典博士 谢谢！
Dr. Meridian, please. Thank you.
我
I.
我想我来早了
guess I'm early.
我有预约
I have an appointment.
我是布鲁斯 韦恩
I'm Bruce Wayne.
很好
Good.
我想你有足够的钱给我买个新门
You can afford a door.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我 我还以为
You sounded like you were in.
对不起 我以为你碰上麻烦了
you know, trouble.
我倒宁可听到你反对合作暴力破门而入的解释
I prefer healthy expressions of violence as opposed to breaking in.
好吧
So.
我能做些什么？
how can I help you?
看 有人不断给我写情书
Someone's been sending me love letters.
一封送到我的办公室 还有一封送到了我家里
One at my office and one at my home.
戈登局长认为你也许可以给我一些专家的忠告
Commissioner Gordon thought you might give me your opinion.
是表
A clock.
Clock.
「撕下我的一个头
"Tear one off and scratch my head.
轻轻一擦 黑变红「
what once was red is black instead."
是火柴
A match.
这写信的人是个不折不扣的疯子
My opinion: This letter writer is a wacko.
疯子？
Wacko?
是专业性术语吗？
That a technical term?
病人可能患有强迫性综合症
Patient may suffer from obsession.
伴随潜在的杀人侵向 你对这个满意吗？
with potential homicidal tendencies. Is that better for you?
这么说 你认为
So, what you're saying is.
这是一个疯子
this guy's a total wacko.
一点不错
Exactly.
他是在追逐你
He's obsessed with you.
他唯一的出路就是清除这个不正常的偏爱
His only escape may be to purge the fixation.
杀了我
To kill me.
我认为你的理解力很强
I think you understand obsession better than you let on.
你喜欢蝙蝠？
You like bats?
那是测试图
That's a Rorschach, Mr. Wayne.
测墨迹的
An inkblot.
人们眼里看到的是他内心所想
People see what they want.
我的问题是：你喜欢蝙蝠吗？
The question is, do you like bats?
还在玩娃娃吗？
Still playing with dolls?
她是马来西亚的梦女士
She's a Malaysian dream warden.
有种文化相信它能保证你不做恶梦
Some cultures believe she protects you from bad dreams.
你肯定认为很傻
It's silly to you, I'm sure.
你看上去那么悲哀
You look so sad.
你需要一个吗？
Do you need one?
我？不 我要它干嘛？
Me? No. Why would I?
你的内心和你的表面很不一样
You're not exactly what you seem, are you?
你究竟为什么而来？
What is it you really came here for?
哦 时间到了
Yikes, time's up.
通常这句话由我来说
That's usually my line.
我非常乐意呆在这儿跟你聊一聊
I'd love to stay here chatting.
是吗？
Would you?
我看不一定
I'm not so sure.
我必须让你脱掉这些衣服
I must get you out of those clothes.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
换上黑色礼服
And into a black dress.
告诉我 博士你喜欢看马戏吗？
Tell me, doctor, do you like the circus?
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
孩子们 朋友们
boys and girls of all ages.
欢迎来到世界上最伟大的马戏表演！
welcome to the greatest show on earth!
和你在一起的那位漂亮女士是谁？
Who is this beautiful young woman you're with?
切斯 马瑞典博士
Dr. Chase Meridian.
博士？
A doctor?
什么样的博士？
What kind of doctor?
今晚是为纽约儿童医院募捐的慈善演出
for Gotham Children's Hospital.
让我们感谢最伟大的捐助人：
Let's thank our largest single donor:
布鲁斯 韦恩先生！
Bruce Wayne!
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
在距地面70英尺的上面
70 feet above the ground.
飞人世家将为大家表演
performing feats of unimaginable aerial skill.
令人惊叹的绝技
the Flying Graysons!
听着
Listen.
这个周末我要去攀岩 你愿不愿意和我一起去？
I'm going rock climbing this weekend. Would you join me?
我倒是很想
I'd like to.
我喜欢攀岩 可是
I love climbing. I really love it.
可是？
But?
我有个约会
I've met someone.
这太快了 你刚搬来不久
That's fast work. You just moved here.
你可以说 他
You could say he.
从天而降
dropped out of the sky and.
砰！
bang!
我想他也有这种感觉
I think he felt it too.
他当然有
He sure did.
什么？
What?
谁会没有呢？
Who wouldn't?
现在
Now.
理查德
Richard.
飞人世家最年青的一位
the youngest flying Grayson.
他将为大家表现最精彩的
will perform the awe-inspiring.
死亡之约
death drop.
他将不用
without the safety.
安全网
of a net!
请大家欣赏
Let's go.
你行的
You'll be okay.
女士们
Ladies.
先生们！
and gentlemen!
现在国际马戏团新的经理请大家忘记
Now, the new management of the circus invites you to forget.
这美好健康的美国娱乐
this good, wholesome fun.
来和我们一起庆祝事故
and join us in a celebration of chaos.
还有正式的公正！
and true jesters!
拿下来！
Bring it on!
现在！
Now!
今晚 我们有一个新的节目
Tonight, a new act for your.
我们叫它 天顶下的大屠杀
personal amazement. We call it Massacre under the Big Top.
现在 大家注意看了
Let us direct your attention to the ring.
正中央 在几个外表美丽的球体里面
Inside this harmless-Iooking orb are two.
有200根炸药
that's two hundred sticks of TNT.
引爆遥控器
And in our innocent hand.
就放在我的手上
a radio detonator.
你到底要什么？
What do you want?
市长大人 要什么？
Want, Mr. Mayor?
很简单 我要蝙蝠侠
One simple thing: Batman.
撕碎他
Bruised, broken, bleeding.
我要他死！
in a word: Dead!
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
我们面前都是些什么人？
Who do we have before us?
纽约城
Gotham's finest.
最有影响力
well-to-do.
最显赫的人
influential.
而你们当中 一定有人知道谁是蝙蝠侠
Surely one of you knows who Batman is.
你们中一个脸色苍白的家伙就是蝙蝠侠！
Hell, odds are one of you pasty-faced twits is Batman!
你只有两分种
You have two minutes.
哈利！
Harvey!
我是蝙蝠侠！
I'm Batman!
我们能制止他们
We can stop them.
从钢丝上爬过去
Go out on the rigging.
小心点
Be careful.
别担心
Don't worry.
快去吧 孩子们！
Go to work, boys!
正合我意
Our kind of day.
抓住它！
Reach for it! Stop it!
天啦
Oh, my God.
你让他住在这太好了 他什么亲人也没有
It's good you took him in. He hasn't anyone now.
整天录证词 没有吃饭 没有睡觉
He filled out papers all day. He hasn't slept or eaten.
欢迎你格里森先生
Welcome, Master Grayson.
我是阿福来德
I'm Alfred.
最近如何 Al？
How you doing, Al?
给你准备一个房间 但也许你想先吃饭？
There's a room prepared for you. But perhaps you'd like to eat first.
哦 我要离开这里
Okay, I'm out of here.
怎样？
Excuse me?
告诉那个警察我在这里
Telling that cop I'd stay here.
会让我少受点那些社工接见
saved me a lot of social service interviews.
不反对 也不感谢 再见
So, no offense, but no thanks. See you.
别在意
Take it easy.
你去哪里？戏团一定在去大都会的半路上
Where will you go? The circus must be halfway to Metropolis.
给双脸人一点颜色瞧瞧
Get a fix on Two-Face.
我会杀掉他
Then I'll kill him.
杀掉他不会让痛苦消失
Killing Two-Face won't take the pain away.
只会更痛苦
It'll make it worse.
别给我说教好不好？
Spare me the sermons, all right?
我不需要你的忠告或怜悯
I don't need your advice or your charity.
好车
Nice bike.
好多车手酒吧外头停着？
Hang out at a lot of biker bars?
你油箱快空拉
You're almost on empty.
到汽车间加一下吧 路上没有加油站
Fill it up in the garage. There's no gas station for miles.
油泵在这里
Pump's over here.
这是汽车间还是汽车博物馆？
Is this a garage or a car museum, Bruce?
这是1917年的哈雷
A 1917 Harley.
是的
Yep.
印第安型的 完全修复
Indian Classic, fully restored.
这个是文森特黑骑士
This is a Vincent Black Knight.
只限量生产100部
They only made 100.
101 实际上 我的最爱
A hundred and one, actually. She's my favorite.
你有两部
You've got two.
那辆坏掉啦
That one doesn't run.
节流阀拆到这部上
Throttle sticks on this one.
阿福来德的好技师 但是
Alfred's a good mechanic, but.
还需要大量工作
these need a lot of work.
如果有人修得好
Someone were to fix them up.
可以拿一辆走
they could keep one.
无论如何
Anyway.
旅途愉快
have a nice trip.
你会好起来的
You'll land on your feet.
小少爷要走？
Is the young master leaving?
可怜
Pity.
那我得扔掉这些 也许狗想吃呢
I'll just toss this away then. Perhaps the dogs are hungry.
嘿 阿尔 等着
Hey, Al, wait up.
布鲁斯主人？
Master Bruce?
象我的双亲一样
Just like my parents.
再次发生
It's happening again.
魔鬼又从黑夜跑出来啦 一声尖叫 两声枪响
A monster comes out of the night, a scream, two shots.
是我害的
I killed them.
你说啥？
What did you say?
是他杀害的
He killed them.
双脸
Two-Face.
他屠杀那孩子的双亲
He slaughtered that boy's parents.
不不
No, no.
你是说；「是我害的」
You said, "I killed them."
照看好那个孩子
Take care of the kid.
当然先生
Certainly, sir.
要我帮你放好 格里森少爷？
Can I help you settle in, Master Grayson?
不
No.
谢谢 我不会呆很长时间的
Thanks, I won't be staying long.
这是知更鸟？
Is this a robin?
我哥哥的钢丝有一次断过 我荡过去抓住他
My brother's wire broke once and I swung out and grabbed him.
我父亲说我是他的英雄
My father said I was his hero.
我飞的象知更鸟一样
I flew in like a robin.
证明我是一个英雄
Some hero I turned out to be.
你父亲是对的
But your father was right.
我可以告诉你 你是英雄
You are a hero. I can tell.
扔掉这个好不好？我不再需要
Throw this away, will you? I won't need it anymore.
我想我就把它放在这里
I think I'll just put it in here.
及时修一下坏翅膀
Broken wings mend in time.
总有一天知更鸟会再次起飞的
One day Robin will fly again.
我保证
I promise.
开车去
We'll drive.
困惑者？
The Puzzler?
赌徒？
The Gamester?
杀人船长？
Captain Kill?
问号面具人？
Question Mark Man?
谢谢 太感谢拉
Thank you. Thank you so much.
蝙蝠顽固地拒绝退场
The Bat's stubborn refusal to expire.
快让大家发疯啦
is driving us insane!
别担心 宝贝
Don't worry, baby.
你很快就能杀死他
You'll kill him soon.
另外
Besides.
我为你准备好你喜欢的：
I made your favorite.
发泡的香槟
Sparkling champagne and.
水煮鲑鱼 小鹌鹑蛋
yummy poached salmon with little quail eggs and a.
奶油
creamy.
幻想
dreamy.
柠檬蛋奶酥
lemon souffle.
不 我的才是你喜欢的：
No, I made your favorite.
烤透的黑野猪心
A charred heart of black boar.
一大片驴排骨肉
a side of raw donkey meat.
烈性酒 干脆点 宝贝！
and a Sterno and grain alcohol, straight up, baby!
好极啦！
Perfect!
女人 把我们宠坏啦！
Ladies, you spoil us!
我们现在犹豫的是该先吃哪个
We're of two minds about what to eat first.
什么？
What?!
我希望你们准备着加座
I hope you made extra.
你是哪个混蛋？
Who the hell are you?
只是一个朋友
Just a friend.
但是你可以叫我
But you can call me.
谜语者
The Riddler.
我要叫你死鬼 那还差不多！你怎样找到这儿来的？说！
I'll call you dead, is more like it! How did you find us? Talk!
不过如果我说出来 那会让你不忍心下手杀我 我的与世隔绝者？
But then if I talked what would keep you from slaying me, O Segregated One?
顺便我得说 不停止采摘就无法收获
That's never going to heal if you don't stop picking.
看看你会不会流绿血
Let's see if you bleed green.
你想杀的不是我
It's not me you want to kill.
象你这样强大的人当然太容易就可以
That's just too easy for someone as powerful as you and.
你
you.
但 蝙蝠侠
But Batman.
是个对手
there's a challenge.
杀掉蝙蝠！听起来主意不错
Kill the Bat! Sounds like a good idea.
但是你是否仔细想过？几个子弹 飞溅的鲜血 ？
But have you thought it through? A few bullets, a splash of blood, then what?
弄湿的手
Wet hands.
狂杀后的沮丧
Post-homicidal depression.
何不先戏弄他？
Why not humiliate him first?
是的
Yeah.
让他暴露弱点 然后 在他最虚弱的时候
Expose his frailties. Then, when he is at his weakest.
干掉他！
crush him!
我看见
I see that.
你左边的眼睛在闪闪发光
sparkle in your left eye.
我可以帮你对付蝙蝠侠
I can help you get Batman.
如果那样
That is, if you'II.
你就得让我多活一点时间
spare my life for just a few moments.
谢谢
Thank you.
我喜欢你在那里干的事 给房子和花来上一点重金属
I love what you've done here. Heavy Metal meets House and Garden.
真漂亮
Beautiful.
如此黑暗 哥特
It's so dark and Gothic and.
颓废
disgustingly decadent.
同时却又如此的轻快
Yet so bright and chipper and.
传统
conservative.
就象你！
It's so you!
是的 也象你！
And yet, so you!
很少有人兼具冬天和春天的双重品格 但是
Very few people are both a summer and a winter, but.
但你却拥有
but you pull it off nicely.
快说出重点？
What's the point?
有人可告诉过你 你有严重的冲动失控症？
Has anyone ever told you you have a serious impulse-control problem?!
这就是重点
This is the point.
这就是我找到你的方法
This is how I found you.
我来给你示范一下
Let me demonstrate.
这是你的大脑在Box里
This is your brain on the Box.
这是我的大脑在Box里
This is my brain.
是不是有人觉得象一只煎熟的鸡蛋？
Does anyone else feel like a fried egg?
我要再来一次
I'll have more.
会再来的 先放过一个
There's more. But only the first one's free.
这是契约：
Here's the bargain:
你要帮我拿下大都会制造
You'll help me steal production capital.
我就把盒子放到这个城市的所有电视机里
so I can put a Box on every TV in town.
成为纽约这个愚人村里的智者 碳基生命形态！
and become Gotham's cleverest carbon-based life form!
作为回报
And in return.
大家都听好啦？
Is everybody paying attention?
我要帮你解开一个最大的谜底
I will help you solve the greatest riddle of all.
那个谜语中的谜语：
The mother of all riddles:
到底谁是
Who is.
蝙蝠侠？
Batman?
你擅闯私地
You broke into our hideout.
玷污这个居所的纯洁
You violated the sanctity of our lair.
应当把你的骨头碾碎
We should crush your bones into powder.
不过你有一个有趣的提议
But you pose an interesting proposition.
因此 正：接受提议 反：打下你的狗头
Therefore, heads, we accept, and tails, we blow your damn head off.
这个好
Here's a good one.
不不不！
No, no, no!
那个好
There is a good one.
- 别管那个 我来 - 我不习惯等待
- Leave that. I'll attend to it. - I'm not used to being waited on.
不要朝我开枪！
Don't shoot me!
不要瞪着我！给我那个！
Don't eyeball me! Give me that!
双脸 给我看看怎样揍他！
Two-Face, show me how to punch a guy!
这个简单小兄弟 捏好你的拳头 收回来
It's dead simple, my boy. Ball up your fist, reach back.
你来一下
and assert yourself.
看起来很有趣 我来试试看
That looks fun. Let me try.
捏起拳头 收回来 爽一下
Ball up the fist, reach way back assert yourself.
十万 2百20
One hundred thousand, two hundred and twenty.
忘记数字啦！
I lost count!
昨天夜间的另一起抢劫案 由绿衣危险分子干下的
Last night another robbery, perpetrated by the green-suited menace.
造成上百万价值的钻石被盗 蝙蝠侠事先未提出警告
resulting in millions in diamonds stolen, with no sign of Batman.
双脸组成的团伙 这个新的犯罪样式
This new criminal's pattern of marking his crimes with puzzles.
根据他犯罪时所带的标记 纽约居民称之为谜语人
has Gothamites calling him The Riddler.
显然你和蝙蝠侠有个共同的敌人
Apparently, you and Batman have a common enemy.
这个是早间邮件一起来的
That was with the morning mail.
「我们8个往前走 不回头
"The eight of us go forth, not back, to protect our king.
保护国王被攻击「
from attack."
象棋的兵
Chess pawns.
钟
Clock.
火柴
Matches.
固体 人造的
All man-made objects.
尺寸小分量轻
Small in size, light in weight.
相互的联系在哪里？
What's the connection?
那就是他被叫做谜语者的道理
With all due respect, that's why they call him The Riddler.
要不要我帮你？
May I help you?
为什么只有这个是锁上的？
Why is this the only locked door?
那后头有什么
What's back there?
韦恩先生死去的妻子
Master Wayne's dead wives.
那是银器室
The silver closet. On your way.
现在 你们可以自己成为情节的一部分！
Now, you can be part of the action!
利格玛技术把3D娱乐带到你的家庭！
Nygma Tech brings the joy of 3-D entertainment into your home!
女士先生们 我来告诉大家
Ladies and gentlemen, let me tell you.
我的想法
my vision.
在美国 让每一个家庭都拥有一个Box
The Box in every home in America.
总有一天 全世界！
and one day, the world!
本地新闻 爱德华利格玛的3D-Box
In local news, Edward Nygma's 3-D Box.
已经成为纽约城疯狂的时尚
has become the rage of Gotham.
昨天晚上售罄一空的电子商店发生混乱
Rioting occurred last night at electronic stores that were sold out.
几乎没有一个家庭不拥有一个Box
There is hardly a home without the Nygma Tech Box.
评论认为Box把纽约居民变成巫术信徒
Critics claim the Box turns Gothamites into zombies.
但爱德华利格玛仅仅耸耸他的肩膀
But Edward Nygma just shrugs.
「电视机刚出现的时候他们也是这样说的 」
"That's what they said when TV was invented."
迪克少爷！
Master Dick!
在这里
Up here.
只是检查一下
Just checking, young sir.
入侵警报 入侵警报
Intruder alert. Intruder alert.
我有东西要给你 在桌上
I have something for you. It's on the table.
希望你喜欢它
I hope you like it.
你可以叫它临床直觉
Call it clinical intuition.
我认为你的梦想需要有一些改变
I thought your dreams needed changing.
我的双亲被杀害
My parents were murdered before me.
那时我还是个孩子
when I was a kid.
我不
I don't.
不记得发生的大部分情况 但是
remember a lot of what happened, but.
但我做梦的时候常常有这样的东西 闪光
what I do comes to me in my dreams. Flashes.
有一些新的东西 虽然 我以前不曾看到过
There's a new element now though, I haven't seen before.
一本红皮书
It's a red leather book.
还有别的
Something else.
现在我醒过来发现它又出现
My dreams come to me when I'm awake now.
布鲁斯 你描述的是一种被压抑的回忆
Bruce, you're describing repressed memories.
遗忘的痛苦景象试图重新浮现
Images of a forgotten pain that's trying to surface.
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
可能你双亲的死状你并不是真正看见的
Is there an aspect of your parents' death you haven't faced?
事情发生的时候你还很年轻
You were so young when it happened.
或许我该让你两个单独呆在一起
Maybe I should leave you two alone.
这个可不单单是把工作带回家这样简单？
This goes way beyond taking your work home, doesn't it?
好吧
All right.
我想他是有魅力的
I think he's fascinating.
冷静
Clinically.
一个人为何要做这些？
Why does a man do this?
似乎他曾经被下过罚他苦行的咒语
It's as if he's cursed to pay penance.
是怎样的罪过让他夜夜受到这样的煎熬？
What crime could he have committed to deserve a life of nightly torture?
那个不仅仅是
It's more than just.
专业兴趣 是不是 切斯？
professional interest, isn't it, Chase?
布鲁斯 你嫉妒？
Bruce, are you jealous?
不
No.
我不会为蝙蝠侠嫉妒
I can't be jealous of Batman.
我想靠近你 但你不让我接近
I want to be close, but you won't let me near.
你有何东西是要向我隐藏的？
What are you protecting me from?
你想知道我？
Do you want to know me?
想知道我是谁？
Do you want to know who I am?
我猜
I guess.
我们都是两个人
we're all two people.
一个在白天 另一个藏在阴影里
One daylight, and the one we keep in shadow.
狂怒
Rage.
强暴
violence.
激情
passion.
很抱歉
Excuse me.
我有事
I'm busy.
很抱歉打扰你 我有一些关于迪克的烦事
I'm sorry to bother you. I have some distressing news about Dick.
他怎样？
Is he okay?
恐怕迪克少爷已经外出啦
I'm afraid Master Dick has gone traveling.
跑出去？
He ran away?
实际上 是开着车
Actually, he took the car.
他开的美洲豹？
He boosted the Jag?
不是
Not the Jaguar.
另一辆
The other car.
本特利？
Bentley?
不 先生
No, sir.
另一辆车
The other car.
来坐坐我这辆可爱的车 宝贝？
Go for a little ride in my love machine, babies?
那是蝙蝠侠！
It's Batman!
打开吧 蝙蝠侠
Open up, Batman.
等等！
Wait!
不是蝙蝠侠！
That's not Batman!
你说的啥意思？
What do you mean?
是蝙蝠男孩！
That's Batboy!
不是蝙蝠！
It ain't the Bat!
让她走！
Let her go!
你是哪一个？
Who the hell are you?
我是蝙蝠侠
I'm Batman.
我忘带我的工作服 好不好？
I forgot my suit, all right?
来吧 快跑！
Come on, run!
蝙蝠侠从未吻过女孩？
Doesn't Batman ever kiss the girl?
走！
Go!
谢谢你 你救我一命！
Thanks, you saved my life!
我可以直接跑进这辆超级英雄快车
I could definitely get into this superhero gig.
蝙蝠侠！
Batman!
私生子！
Bastard!
这不该是你！
It should've been you!
如果你在剧场告诉双脸你是谁
If you had told Two-Face who you were at the circus.
他们就都会还活着
they'd still be alive!
如果布鲁斯威恩能够替你的双亲去死 他会的
If Bruce Wayne could've given his life for your family, he would have.
我天天想的就是抓住双脸
All I can think about every day is getting Two-Face.
他占据我的整个生活
He took my whole life.
今晚我在这里
When I was out there tonight.
我想象跟我打的就是他
I imagined it was him I was fighting.
甚至当我打你的时候
even when I was fighting you.
痛苦消失啦
and the pain went away.
你理解？
Do you understand?
是的
Yes, I do.
好
Good.
你必须帮我找到他
You must help me find him.
那以后
When we do.
由我来杀死他
I'm the one who kills him.
那 你想让你的整个生活？
So, you're willing to take a life?
都围绕着双脸
As long as it's Two-Face.
事情肯定会这样：
Then it will happen this way:
你杀掉他
You make the kill.
但你的痛苦不会消失 反而会生长
And your pain doesn't die with Harvey, it grows.
你就会钻到黑夜里去找另一个脸 一个
So you run into the night to find another face, and another.
接着一个
and another.
直到一天早晨你发现
until one terrible morning you wake up and realize.
复仇已经成为你整个的生活
that revenge has become your whole life.
你不知道这一切如何发生
and you won't know why.
你不懂
You can't understand.
你的家人被一个疯子残杀
Your family wasn't killed by a maniac.
是的
Yes, they were.
跟我一样
We're the same.
如果一样 何不帮助我 训练我 让我做你的搭档
If we're the same, help me. Train me, let me be your partner.
不
No.
我不能
I can't.
你还有别的选择
You still have a choice.
听着布鲁斯
Look, Bruce.
不管你喜不喜欢 我已经成为这个事情的一部分
I'm a part of this, like it or not.
今晚整个纽约社交界都来参加他的宴会
Tonight all of Gotham society has turned out for Edward Nygma's.
庆祝他的新产品Box的发布
gala unveiling of his New Improved Box.
谢谢你阿尔
Thanks, Al.
是我的荣幸 先生
My pleasure, sir.
他们将要宴聚 跳舞到天亮
They'll be dining and dancing the night away.
在纽约里兹饭店的屋顶上
on the glamorous roof of the Ritz Gotham.
你的脸出现在所有杂志的所有角落你有何感想？
What's it like to have your face on the cover of every magazine?
爱德华 成为这个城市新进的钻石王老五有何感想？
Edward, how does it feel to be the city's newest, most eligible bachelor?
纽约必须知道！
Gotham must know!
那是布鲁斯威恩！
There's Bruce Wayne!
布鲁斯！
Brucie!
哦 爱迪 他真伶俐！
Oh, Eddie, he is too cute!
你穿这个套装怎就找不到这个感觉？
How come you don't look so good in that suit?
闭嘴 你是来工作的！
Shut up. You're here to work!
我的胎记如何？
How's my mole?
很好
Fine.
Nygma技术收购威恩娱乐的传言你如何评价？
What about rumors of a Nygma Tech takeover of Wayne Enterprises?
Nygma技术的股票比威恩娱乐超卖一倍
Nygma Tech stock is outselling Wayne Enterprises 2 to 1.
你昨天的新闻吧 布鲁斯？
Are you yesterday's news, Bruce?
布鲁斯 老先生
Bruce, old man.
报道说到超卖 超值 超量
The press wonders what it's like to be outsold, outclassed, out-coiffed and.
超任何地方
generally outdone in every way.
你好 爱德华 祝贺你
Hello, Edward. Congratulations.
盛大的宴会 漂亮的套装
Great party. Nice suit.
好
Wit. Good.
你呢？
And you are?
切斯
Chase.
你一定在进行一个非常重要的工作
And what a grand pursuit you must be.
我是布鲁斯威恩 小姐 ？
I'm Bruce Wayne, Miss?
你可以随便叫我
You can call me anything you want.
女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
未来！
the future!
我新近开发的Box将提供给你全新的交互全息幻象
My New Improved Box offers fully-interactive holographic fantasies.
爱德华 你真是天才
Edward, you're dashing and a genius.
你怎样创造出这些影象的 宝贝？
How do you create these images, hon?
那个 亲爱的 是我的小秘密
That, my dear, is my little secret.
交互式全息图
Fully-interactive holographs.
定向高频载波 射入大脑
Only a high-frequency carrier wave, beamed into the brain.
就能够创造这些影象
could create such images.
你想研究一下
And you wish you thought of it.
不要做痛苦的失败者
Don't be a sore loser.
走进去 试试看
Step inside. Give it a try.
如果你能够让影象进入思想 还有啥东西可以阻挡你
If you can introduce images into the mind, what stops you from.
把影象从思想里提取出来？
extracting images out of the mind?
不敢试用我的机器？只能这样说
Too timid to try my machine? Just say so.
跳个舞？
Shall we dance?
调皮鬼 调皮鬼
Naughty, naughty.
找东西？
Looking for something?
只是在想如何关掉它
I was just wondering how you turn it off.
好
Clever.
谢谢
Thanks.
不用谢
My pleasure.
晚上好 威恩先生
Good evening, Mr. Wayne.
放松
Relax.
告诉我你的
Tell me your.
梦
dreams.
告诉我
Tell me.
你的幻想
your fantasies.
告诉我你的秘密
Tell me your secrets.
告诉我
Tell me.
你最深
your deepest.
最黑暗的
darkest.
恐惧
fears.
大家放松！
Relax, folks!
只是老派的 低技术的强盗！
It's only an old-fashioned low-tech stick-up!
我门感兴趣的东西是：
We're interested in the basics!
现金 珠宝 移动电话
Cash, jewelry, cellular telephones.
快点安静地交出来 不会受到伤害！
Hand them over nice and quietly, and no one will be hurt!
紧急 阿尔弗雷德
Emergency, Alfred.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
大家安静！
Be calm, everybody!
保持安静！
Just stay calm!
很抱歉！
Excuse me!
你毁掉我的宴会！你有病？
You're ruining my big party! Are you insane?!
等你把蝙蝠侠送过来等的心焦
We're sick of waiting for you to deliver Batman.
耐心的 双重人
Patience, O Bifurcated One.
耐心 去他的 我想让他死
Patience, hell, we want him dead!
一次小小的伤害和谋杀最有效
And nothing brings out the Batman like a little murder and mayhem!
你会让我被抓住的
You could have let me in on the caper.
可以组织 计划 预售电影改编权
We could have organized it, planned it pre-sold the movie rights!
你的出场不错 他的更好
Your entrance was good, his was better.
不同在哪里？
The difference?
表演技巧
Showmanship!
紧急 阿尔弗雷德
Emergency, Alfred.
是的 先生
Oh, sir.
我能先点火
I could be fired for this.
也许我得回到白金汉宫
I'll go back to Buckingham Palace.
好 孩子们内第二阶段
All right, boys! Phase Two!
半夜 我的地方
My place, midnight.
不会有比瓦斯更坏的环境啦
Nothing like a bad case of gas!
你怎就老不肯死？
Why can't you just die?!
喂
Hi.
你在干啥？
What were you doing?!
你处于一种无法感谢的尴尬境地你可知道？
You got a real gratitude problem, you know that?
我得起个名 蝙蝠小子？飞武士？
I need a name. Batboy? Knight Wing?
搭档该起个怎样的名？
What's a good sidekick name?
「迪克格雷森 大学生」
"Dick Grayson, college student."
滚蛋吧
Screw you!
我救你 你欠我的
I saved your life. You owe me.
你会让自己被杀死的
You're going to get yourself killed.
我是你的搭档
I'm your new partner.
不
No!
你晚上到哪里 我都会看着 蝙蝠侠到哪里 我都会跟着
Whenever you go out at night, I'll be watching. Where Batman goes, I'll go.
你如何阻止我？
How will you stop me?
我能的
I can stop you.
把这个跟蝙蝠装挂到一起
Hang this next to the Batsuit.
它属于那里
where it belongs.
你鼓励他
You're encouraging him.
怀着复仇之心的年轻人要给一点鼓励
Young men with a mind for revenge need little encouragement.
他们需要引导
They need guidance.
你 首先必须知道你的生活是你自己选择的
You, above all, should know the consequences of the life you choose.
甚至切斯都说蝙蝠侠是在受罪
Even Chase calls being Batman a curse.
也许这位小姐就是一种医治方法
Perhaps the lady's just what the doctor ordered.
她看上去可爱聪慧
She seems lovely and wise.
以前我从未爱过
I've never been in love before.
去找她
Go to her.
把感情告诉她
Tell her how you feel.
她想要的是蝙蝠侠 不是布鲁斯威恩
She wants Batman, not Bruce Wayne.
让她决定
Let her decide.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我无法相信
I can't believe this.
我从第一次见你就盼望这个时刻
I've imagined this moment since I first saw you.
你的眼睛
Your eyes.
嘴唇
your lips.
身体
Your body.
现在我能够得到
And now I have you and.
但我却希望这是另外一个人
I'm wishing you were somebody else.
我猜想总有一天女孩会长大
I guess a girl has to grow up sometime.
我碰到一个人
I've met someone.
他不是你
He's not you.
希望你理解
I hope you can understand.
我懂
I understand.
好吧
Well.
那正是我说的
That's just what I said.
那时我在教我的小狗狗一个新玩意：
Then I taught my doggie a new trick:
如何勾画出人心
How to map the human mind.
你想看到布鲁斯威恩脑袋里的东西不想？
Would you like to see what Bruce Wayne has in his head?
猜猜我这个：
Riddle me this:
哪个人
What kind of man.
脑袋里有蝙蝠在飞？
has bats on the brain?
- 来吧 你猜的到 - 你是个天才
- Go ahead. You can say it. - You're a genius.
停下
Oh, stop.
因此 从今天起
So, from this day on.
蝙蝠侠不再存在
Batman is no more.
你不可以退出
You can't just quit.
外头还有罪恶 蝙蝠侠必须保护无辜者
There's monsters out there. Batman has to protect the innocent.
我已经把自己献身给帮助我不认识的人
I've dedicated my life to helping strangers I've never met.
我从未见过的脸
Faces I've never seen.
好
Well.
无辜者不会再无脸
the innocent aren't faceless anymore.
你不能告诉我我的余生该怎样干
You can't tell me what to do with the rest of my life.
我父亲对我说各人走自己的路
My dad told me that every man goes his own way.
我的路通向双脸
My way goes to Two-Face.
你必须帮助我
You must help me.
如果你找到哈维
And if you do find Harvey.
把他杀掉
and then kill him.
那以后呢？
what next?
当然
Exactly.
你会象我一样孤独
Then you'd be alone, like me.
不 你必须让我去做
No, you must let this go.
听我说 我是你的朋友
Listen to me, I'm your friend.
我不需要一个朋友 我需要一个搭档
I don't need a friend, I need a partner.
双脸必须偿还
Two-Face has got to pay.
求你
Please.
切斯来吃晚饭 我会告诉她
Chase is coming for dinner. I'm going to tell her.
所有的一切
everything.
上楼来 好好谈谈
Come upstairs. We'll talk.
- 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
万圣节快乐
Happy Halloween.
Happy Halloween to you.
我让你今晚到这里来是想告诉你一些事情
I asked you here tonight because there's something I wanted to tell you.
我也想告诉你一些事情
I wanted to tell you something too.
我想的是…
What I wanted.
说下去 你先
Go ahead, you first.
是一个诡计
Trick or treat!
我一直以来
All my life I have been.
都被一个真正的男人吸引
attracted to a certain kind of man.
其实是错的
The wrong kind.
看看我过的生活
And look what I do for a living.
自从
And since.
自从遇见你 我
since I met you, I.
哦 天
Oh, God.
我是不是发神经？
Why am I so nervous?
今晚别吃的太多 会在床上生病的
Don't eat too much tonight or you'll be sick in your beds.
万圣节快乐
Happy Halloween!
怎样？
What's wrong?
又来啦
It's happening again.
闪光
Flashes.
我家人的死
My parents' death.
你的记忆想冲出来
Your memories are trying to surface.
我要告诉你一些事情
I want to tell you something.
我以前从未对别人说过
Something I've never told anyone.
好的
It's all right.
放松 我在这里
It's all right. I'm here.
我在这里
I'm here.
我家人的守丧夜
The night of my parents' wake.
神甫的话不能让我平静
the priest's words gave no comfort.
当然
Of course.
我父亲的书桌
There, on my father's desk.
红皮书
the red book.
他的日记
His journal.
他天天写的
He wrote in it every day.
但现在他无法再写
But now he'd never write in it again.
那一刻我知道
At that moment I knew.
我的生活会有所不同
my life would never be the same.
我跑到外头暴风雨里
I raced out into the storm.
想摆脱愤怒
trying to outrun the rage.
痛苦
The pain.
我感觉到
Then I fell.
我始终感觉到
I fell forever.
巨大的黑洞
The cave was monstrous.
一定在那里有上万年
It must have been there for centuries.
那里头
And there.
深深的阴影
deep in the shadows.
我看见
I saw.
有东西朝我逼近
It was coming toward me.
一开始我害怕 只是一开始
I was scared at first, but only at first.
黑暗中的影子是我的注定
The figure in the dark was my destiny.
这个改变我的生活
It would change my life forever.
我把这个与罪犯心中的恐惧相对抗
I would use its image to strike terror into the hearts of those who did evil.
我想让这些事情不再在别人身上发生
I would ensure what happened to me would never happen to anyone else.
我要报仇
I would have my revenge.
你想对我说的是？
What are you trying to tell me?
我是
I'm.
小鬼登门！
Twick or tweet!
诡计
Trick.
记住计划？
Remember the plan?
要活捉
Seize and capture.
不要杀死
No killing.
可以让你增加力量
That goes double for you.
如果我是超级英雄
If I was a superhero.
我会躲到哪里？
where would I hide?
打屁股
Spank me.
紧急警报 紧急警报
Intruder alert! Intruder alert! Intruder alert!
Intruder alert! Intruder alert!
闭嘴
Shut up!
现在 是留下印记的时候啦
Now, that's impressive!
把驯服的动物带到旷野里总是有危险
It's always risky introducing a tamed animal into the wild.
他们对适应新环境有困难
They may have trouble adapting to their new environment.
可有人告诉胖姐姐
Somebody tell the fat lady.
她只有5岁
she's on in five.
「Joygasm！」
Joygasm!
抓住女孩
Get the girl!
不要杀他
Don't kill him.
如果杀掉他
If you kill him.
他就无法学习事情啦
he won't learn nothing.
布鲁斯先生！
Master Bruce!
你怎样 年轻人？
How are you, young man?
你一直不来叫我
You haven't called me that for a long time.
顽固的老习惯
Old habits die hard.
你还好？
Are you okay?
切斯在哪里？
Where's Chase?
恐怕被抓走啦
I'm afraid they've taken her.
迪克少爷走掉啦
Master Dick has run away.
洞穴被破坏
The cave has been destroyed.
又有一个谜语
And there's another riddle.
我来啦 宝贝
I'm coming, my sweet.
喜不喜欢这件夹克？
Like the jacket?
会让我很安全的当我
It keeps me safe when I'm.
晚上出去跑步
jogging at night.
蝙蝠侠会来救我
Batman will come for me.
蝙蝠侠？
Batman?
你说蝙蝠侠？
Batman, you say?
来救你？
Coming for you?
我可
I'm.
算到这一点
counting on it.
这个怎样一回事？从哪里弄来的？
What is that? Where's it coming from?
那里！
There!
谁干的？
Who's doing that?
谜语者
The Riddler!
「我们是日常所见的5件物品
"We're five little items of an everyday sort.
你可以在网球场找得到「
You'll find us all in a tennis court."
在
In.
A-E-I-O-U
A-E-I-O-U.
元音
Vowels.
并非不聪明 先生
Not entirely unclever, sir.
但跟钟 火柴 棋子有何关系
But what do a clock, a match, chess pawns.
共有的元音 谜语意味着
and vowels have in common? What do these riddles mean?
谜语都有一个数字 顺序是：
Every riddle contains a number and they arrived in this order:
13 1 8
13, 1, 8.
和 5
and 5.
13 1 8 和 5
13, 1, 8 and 5.
意味着？
Meaning?
字母表
Letters of the alphabet?
当然 13是M
Of course, 13 is M.
1是A 8是H 还有 5是E
1 would be A, 8 would be H and 5 would be E.
M-A-H-E
M-A-H-E.
也许1和8是18
Perhaps 1 and 8 are 18.
18是R
18 is "R".
M-R-E
M-R-E.
你觉得这个怎样
How about.
「E先生」？
"Mr. E"?
- 秘密？- 秘密的另一个说法？
- Mystery? - Another name for mystery?
Enigma
Enigma.
E Nygma先生
Mr. E. Nygma.
Edward Nygma
Edward Nygma.
Stickley的自杀是电脑伪造的
Stickley's suicide was obviously a computer-generated forgery.
你确实很聪明 不管别人怎样说
You really are quite bright, despite what people say.
蝙蝠装都被毁掉啦？
Are all the Batsuits destroyed?
还有声纳改装的那个 但未经测试
All except the prototype with the sonar modifications. But it's not tested.
今晚很好
Tonight's a good night.
你有何建议？海水
What do you suggest? By sea.
还是通过空气？
or by air?
何不两者兼具？
Why not both.
你的裁缝是谁？
Who's your tailor?
借用你的 先生
I took the liberty, sir.
「R？」
R?
代表意思是？
What's that stand for?
罗宾
Robin.
谜语者和双脸得到一对死亡对手
Riddler and Two-Face can make a pretty lethal combination.
你可以用一只手
You can use a hand.
2对2比较合理
Two against two are better odds.
我一定会杀掉哈维
I can't promise I won't kill Harvey.
「男人要走自己的路」
A man's got to go his own way.
一个朋友这样对我说过
A friend taught me that.
不仅仅是一个朋友
Not just a friend.
一个搭档
A partner.
他不会来的
He's not coming.
关上吧
Shut it down.
等一下 等一下
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
嘿 向前冲吧
Hey, go!
A-14
A-14.
对
Hit!
好
Sweet!
B-12
B-12.
对
Hit!
我喜欢维生素
My favorite vitamin.
被淹的感受
That sinking feeling.
我喜欢这个游戏
I like this game.
C-9
C-9!
你沉掉我的战舰
You sunk my battleship!
谁 我？
Who, me?
这是你的船长说的
This is your captain speaking.
回到你的座位上 要遭遇紊流
Please return to your seats. We will be experiencing turbulence.
我抓到他啦
I got him!
我希望能够找到黑匣子
I hope they can find the little black box.
现在
Now.
真正的游戏开始啦
the real game begins.
全是生锈的金属 蝙蝠侠
Holy rusted metal, Batman!
海底 全是金属
The ground, it's all metal.
全是洞穴 洞
It's full of holes. Holy.
等一下
Wait!
整个岛在移动
The whole island's moving!
找我们？
Looking for us?
这个为我妈
For my mother!
这是为我爸
My father!
为我哥
My brother!
这个是为我自己
And this is for me!
最终 正义会实现
Finally, justice is served!
让我死
Let us die!
你会继承我的心 儿子
You're a man after our own heart, son!
我会在地狱见到你
I'll see you in hell!
我更想在监狱见到你
I'd rather see you in jail!
哦 好孩子 好孩子
Oh, good boy. Good boy.
蝙蝠把你调教的不错
The Bat's taught you well.
尊贵
Noble.
愚蠢
Stupid.
但尊贵
but noble.
猜猜这个
Riddle me this.
猜猜那个
Riddle me that.
谁害怕大黑蝠？
Who's afraid of the big black bat?
不要再耍诡计 爱德华
No more tricks, Edward.
很好 那
Very well, then.
来真家伙吧
Let's get real.
放掉切斯 这是你我之间的事情
Release Chase. This is between us.
我
And me.
而我
and me!
你吸取纽约人的脑电波 现在你可以阅读人的思想
You've sucked Gotham's brain waves and now you've devised a way to read minds.
当然
You betcha!
很快我的小盒子会遍布整个世界的电视机
Soon my little Box will be on countless TV's around the world.
给我带来信用卡
feeding me credit card numbers.
银行帐号
bank codes.
性幻想
sexual fantasies.
和小小的白色谎言
and little white lies.
他们会走进我的头脑
Into my head they'll go.
成功是可以想见的
Victory is inevitable.
因为知识的力量是无穷的
For if knowledge is power.
所以上帝
then a god.
就是
am.
我！
I!
那是否就是最高理想？我现在还不能告诉你
Was that over the top? I can never tell.
顺便告诉你 我还要看看你的思想 畸形怪物
By the way, I've seen your mind. Freak!
你是最大的谜语
Yours is the greatest riddle of all!
布鲁斯威恩跟蝙蝠侠是否能共存？
Can Bruce Wayne and Batman ever truly coexist?
今天将要揭晓
We'll find out today!
但首先 请出不同意见者
But first, let's meet our contestants.
帘布之后
Behind curtain.
第一位
number one.
才华惊人的切斯 玛瑞迪安博士
the absolutely fabulous Dr. Chase Meridian!
她喜欢徒步旅行 修剪指甲
She enjoys hiking, manicures.
痴痴的想成为布鲁斯生活中的爱
and foolishly hopes to be the love of Bruce's life.
第二位
Number two:
肥蝙蝠的一个也是唯一一个搭档
Fatman's one and only partner.
这个杂耍戏子和孤儿
This acrobat turned orphan.
喜欢星期六早上的动画片 幻想有一天
likes Saturday morning cartoons and dreams of one day being.
跟一个女孩赤身裸体在一起
bare-naked with a girl.
在这些不同意见者的下头
And below these contestants.
是我的一点个人爱好：
my personal favorite:
水的地狱
A watery grave.
轻轻的一按
Just one little touch.
五秒钟以后2个参加者就要
and five seconds later these two players are.
葬身在岩石上
gull feed on the rocks below.
不够时间两个一起救
Not enough time to save them both.
蝙蝠侠 你救哪个？
Which one will it be, Batman?
布鲁斯的爱人？
Bruce's love?
还是黑夜武士的小搭档？
Or the Dark Knight's junior partner?
想不出办法如何救他和我自己
There is no way for me to save them or myself.
是一个巨大的死亡陷阱
It's all one giant death-trap.
决定？
Judges?
抱歉 你的回答必须用提问的形式
I'm sorry. Your answer must be in the form of a question.
不过谢谢你的参加
But thanks for playing.
等一下
Wait!
我有一个给你的题
I have a riddle.
给我？
For me?
真的？
Really?
说说吧
Tell me.
我看不用看
I see without seeing.
对我而言 黑夜跟白天一样清楚
To me, darkness is as clear as daylight.
我是谁？
What am I?
请
Please!
你是个瞎蝙蝠
You're as blind as a bat!
正确
Exactly.
混蛋
Bummer!
谢谢
Thanks.
那些大话都毫无意义
All those heroics for nothing.
不再出题 不再有帘子和第一第二
No more riddles, no more curtains one and two.
只有彻底的结束
Just plain curtains!
你忘记一件事情？
Aren't you forgetting something?
硬币
Your coin.
你总是有两颗心
You're always of two minds.
是的 当然 你是对的
Yes, of course. You're right.
感情是正确判断之敌
Emotion's always the enemy of justice.
你总是一个好朋友
You've always been a good friend.
为什么
Why?
为何我不能
Why can't I.
杀掉你？
kill you?
太多问题
Too many questions.
可怜的爱德华
Poor Edward.
我必须救两个
I had to save them both.
你知道 我既是布鲁斯又是蝙蝠侠
You see, I'm both Bruce Wayne and Batman.
不是因为不得不
Not because I have to be.
现在
Now.
这是我的选择
because I choose to be.
谢谢你前来帮助我会诊 玛瑞迪安博士
Thank you for responding to my request for a consultation, Dr. Meridian.
爱德华
Edward Nygma.
连续几个小时尖叫说他知道
has been screaming for hours that he knows the true identity.
蝙蝠侠的真实身份
of Batman.
爱德华？
Edward?
谁
Who.
是谁？
is it?
我是切斯博士
It's Dr. Meridian. Chase.
你可记得我？
Do you remember me?
我怎能忘记？
How could I forget?
伯顿博士告诉我
Dr. Burton tells me.
你知道蝙蝠侠是谁
you know who Batman is.
我可以告诉你只要你不对我说「请」
I can't tell you if you don't say, "please."
爱德华 请
Edward, please.
谁是蝙蝠侠？
Who is Batman?
我
I'm.
我是蝙蝠侠
Batman.
秘密安全啦
Your secret is safe.
他完全精神失常
He is definitely a wacko.
「精神失常？」
Wacko.
是一个专业说法？
Is that a technical term?
听着
Listen.
我不再需要这个
I won't need this anymore.
谢谢你给我新的梦
Thank you for giving me a new dream.
不要工作太晚
Don't work too late.